{
    "id": "a8e2294d79e548ea8eda419200be5058",
    "title": "Present Or Future Tense",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Granny’s plane ……………………….. at three o’clock.",
            "description": "We use the simple present tense to talk about events which are part of a timetable.",
            "answers": [
                "arrive",
                "arrives",
                "will arrive"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e6f54e09eec4456eb8613817fa14212d"
        },
        {
            "question": "The next semester …………………………. on November 10th.",
            "description": "We use the simple present tense to talk about events which are part of a timetable.",
            "answers": [
                "begin",
                "begins",
                "will begin"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9049102848b748ca934e99028bea8c12"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will pay you back when I ………………… a job.",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the future tense, we use a present tense in the subordinate clause to refer to the future.",
            "answers": [
                "get",
                "got",
                "will get"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "98ecb257e54c4ff49b5180acaafbfaa8"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will call you when dinner ………………………… ready.",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the future tense, we use a present tense in the subordinate clause to refer to the future.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "will be"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "0019761ff8924188855634008a0f0655"
        },
        {
            "question": "Rani ………………………….. for a drink.",
            "description": "The present continuous is often used to talk about future events when the arrangement already exists.",
            "answers": [
                "comes",
                "will come",
                "is coming"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "63bfce16bdae49a5977f16c431b73d22"
        },
        {
            "question": "‘The phone is ringing.’ ‘I …………………… it.’",
            "description": "We use the simple future to announce decisions taken at the moment of speaking.",
            "answers": [
                "will answer",
                "answer",
                "am answering"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "575ea72bb8e545d0908d3083d41ea804"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………….. the tickets but you have to buy the dinner.",
            "description": "We use the simple future tense to talk about our decisions and intentions. ",
            "answers": [
                "will buy",
                "would buy",
                "should buy"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2f41f164bba14d8daa8fa69402e364b3"
        },
        {
            "question": "I think I ……………………….. it.",
            "description": "We do not use the simple present or present continuous to announce decisions that are made at the moment of speaking.",
            "answers": [
                "buy",
                "am buying",
                "will buy"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "7d6fd48d47e04240aa2b8d3931a9b4cc"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… I open a window?",
            "description": "We use shall in questions asking for instructions and decisions.",
            "answers": [
                "Shall",
                "Will",
                "Would"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d659c2a3b0204e38b5b8dfe27974afc5"
        },
        {
            "question": "Let’s go and see her, …………………………. we?",
            "description": "We use shall in question tags after let.",
            "answers": [
                "should",
                "shall",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "64bdd008b4d041bbae629c9d9d4c2382"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………… you get me some apples when you’re out?",
            "description": "We use will to ask people to do things.",
            "answers": [
                "Shall",
                "Should",
                "Will"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "7ec1cd52ca7e492d9a2b6622fa3fd7e3"
        },
        {
            "question": "Get me a cup of coffee, ………………………… you?",
            "description": "We use will in instructions. ",
            "answers": [
                "shall",
                "should",
                "will"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "88ba89dbd01040b2913d0b45576c1f26"
        }
    ]
}